All right so let's look at the graph and I'm going to ask you to remember it because well remember the
好吧，让我们看一下图表，我会要求你记住它，因为记住
the basic idea of it.
它的基本思想。
Because I'm going to get rid of it to go over the example of how we describe it because I don't have
因为我要摆脱它来复习我们如何描述它的例子，因为我没有
that much room on the screen.
屏幕上有那么多空间。
OK.
好的。
So total fertility rate that means the number of babies born and GDP per capita.
所以总生育率是指出生婴儿的数量和人均GDP。
We know what that means.
我们知道这意味着什么。
OK.
好的。
Now here we have on this graph we have the total fertility rate over here.
现在，我们在这张图表上看到了总生育率。
That means the number of children per woman in what those cities states.
这意味着这些城市所规定的每个妇女的孩子数量。
What.
什么。
Well there is Saudi Arabia.
好吧，还有沙特阿拉伯。
There's Israel.
有以色列。
So it's going it's going to be countries.
所以它会是国家。
It's gonna be countries.
这将是国家。
So they each dot is a country.
所以他们每个点都是一个国家。
We can know that because we see that these two dots are countries.
我们可以知道，因为我们看到这两个点是国家。
And maybe you can look up where your country is what is the GDP per capita of your country.
也许您可以查看您所在国家/地区的人均GDP是多少。
What is the fertility rate of your country.
你们国家的生育率是多少。
Maybe interesting to look up to research.
研究起来可能很有趣。
Look up means research.
仰望意味着研究。
OK.
好的。
So and by the way I'm just getting this information from the internet.
所以顺便说一句，我只是从互联网上获取这些信息。
If it's incorrect for some reason I apologize.
如果由于某种原因不正确，我深表歉意。
But we're using it for the example to describe the data because we need to know how to do this.
但是我们在示例中使用它来描述数据，因为我们需要知道如何做到这一点。
All right now we have the fertility rate here and on the.
好吧，现在我们在这里和那里都有生育率。
That's called the y axis.
这就是所谓的y轴。
And on the x axis y axis on the x axis we have the GDP per capita.
在 x 轴上，在 x 轴上的 y 轴上，我们有人均 GDP。
And this is in U.S. dollars and the year we can see is two thousand four.
这是美元，我们可以看到的年份是 2004 年。
So this information comes from two thousand four.
所以这个信息来自两千四。
So we have here we could say very very poor countries low GDP per capita wealthier countries up to 40.
所以我们在这里可以说非常非常贫穷的国家人均GDP低，富裕国家高达40。
Looks like about forty one thousand dollars GDP per capita.
看起来人均GDP大约是四万美元。
And then on the side of the poor countries you have generally higher fertility rate.
然后在贫穷国家这一边，生育率普遍较高。
That means more women are having more babies.
这意味着更多的女性生了更多的孩子。
OK.
好的。
Women are having more babies on average.
女性平均生育更多的孩子。
And then you can see a sharp drop or a sharp decline in the number of babies that women have as the
然后你可以看到女性的婴儿数量急剧下降或急剧下降
GDP per capita increases.
人均国内生产总值增加。
Now if that's complicated and you can understand what I'm saying don't worry we're going to go over
现在，如果这很复杂，并且您可以理解我在说什么，请不要担心，我们将继续
it in text I'm going to read through the example that I've made to describe this and hopefully it will
我将通读我为描述这一点而制作的示例，希望它会
be very clear.
非常清楚。
I'm using this as a way to show you the language we can use to describe visualizations to describe charts
我用它来向你展示我们可以用来描述可视化的语言来描述图表
graphs data.
图表数据。
OK.
好的。
So I hope I hope you can sort of take a mental picture of this and notice the trend here.
所以我希望我希望你能对此有所了解，并注意这里的趋势。
Notice that these countries are the poorer countries the wealthier countries over here.
请注意，这些国家是较贫穷的国家，也是较富裕的国家。
Notice that we have two countries here in the middle.
请注意，我们在中间有两个国家。
And notice these numbers of nine at the top here.
请注意这里顶部的九个数字。
Forty five thousand at the top or at the farthest end over here.
四万五千在顶端或最远的尽头。
OK.
好的。
So take a mental picture.
所以拍一张心理照片。
Ready.
准备好。
One two three.
一二三。
All right.
好的。
Let's now go on and talk about how we can describe this.
现在让我们继续讨论如何描述这一点。
No analysis yet.
还没有分析。
We're not going to talk about what it means yet but we're going to talk about how to describe it clearly.
我们不打算讨论它的含义，但我们将讨论如何清楚地描述它。